<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>Hysterical</title>
  <description>Named 2025 Ambies© Podcast of the Year, Hysterical investigates a mysterious illness that spreads among a group of high school girls in upstate New York. What is causing their sudden, often violent symptoms? Is there something in the water or inside the school? Or is it “all in their head?” The series examines the outbreak in LeRoy, NY, believed by some to be the most severe case of mass hysteria since the Salem Witch Trials. In his search for answers, Dan Taberski (9/12, Missing Richard Simmons, Running from Cops) explores other seemingly inexplicable events of the last few years – CIA officers being crippled with nausea and vertigo; cops OD'ing from exposure to fentanyl – and discovers they’re far more connected than we realize.From Wondery and Pineapple Street Studios, this 7-part series forces us to grapple with the mysteries of our own minds, and reckon with a contagion that we thought was long dead, but may be the defining disorder of our time.Binge all episodes of Hysterical exclusively and ad-free, right now on Wondery+. Start your free trial in the Wondery App, Apple Podcasts, Spotify or by visiting wondery.com/links/hysterical/ now.</description>
  <link>https://podimo.com/dk/shows/221b8814-9340-45ce-93d9-ba08d87f9eec</link>
  <image>
   <url>https://cdn.podimo.com/images/de738d88-a6aa-41a0-bdc5-c2333f168e03_400x400.png</url>
   <title>Hysterical</title>
   <link>https://podimo.com/dk/shows/221b8814-9340-45ce-93d9-ba08d87f9eec</link>
  </image>
  <item>
   <title>What to Listen to Next - MrBallen's Medical Mysteries</title>
   <description>On Hysterical, you heard how the mind has the power to cause physical symptoms in the body, opening the door to terrifying possibilities. But what happens when the body revolts first? Dive into the unknown mysteries of the body with MrBallen. 

MrBallen’s Medical Mysteries delivers horror stories that are clinically proven to get under your skin. From bizarre, unheard-of diseases and miraculous recoveries to strange medical mishaps and unexplainable deaths, your blood is sure to run cold in this unique collaboration between MrBallen and Wondery.

See Privacy Policy at https://art19.com/privacy [https://art19.com/privacy] and California Privacy Notice at https://art19.com/privacy#do-not-sell-my-info [https://art19.com/privacy#do-not-sell-my-info].</description>
   <guid isPermaLink="false">46ff62e4-e2e2-4134-873e-c0995c9bacfe</guid>
   <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
   <enclosure url="https://rss.art19.com/episodes/034a64a8-df69-4ebf-9765-0a90412f3327.mp3?rss_browser=BAhJIgtQb2RpbW8GOgZFVA%3D%3D--dac5a739e2488b244c713a3c754b2eb4e45f1ea7" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/>
   <itunes:duration>00:32:22</itunes:duration>
   <itunes:image href="https://cdn.podimo.com/images/de738d88-a6aa-41a0-bdc5-c2333f168e03_400x400.png"/>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Outbreak | 1</title>
   <description>In the fall of 2011, a high school girl in LeRoy, New York falls ill: spasms, outbursts, and uncontrollably violent movements. As the mysterious illness spreads throughout the school, a young doctor attempts to connect the dots. Is there an external pathogen? Or is what’s happening in LeRoy something far more mysterious?

Listen to Hysterical on the Wondery App or wherever you get your podcasts. Binge all episodes of Hysterical early and ad-free right now by joining Wondery+ in the Wondery App, Apple Podcasts or Spotify. Start your free trial by visiting wondery.com/links/hysterical/ [https://wondery.com/links/hysterical/] now. 

See Privacy Policy at https://art19.com/privacy [https://art19.com/privacy] and California Privacy Notice at https://art19.com/privacy#do-not-sell-my-info [https://art19.com/privacy#do-not-sell-my-info].</description>
   <guid isPermaLink="false">97c9378d-ce80-49e2-b177-9e4bb0a9a229</guid>
   <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 07:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
   <enclosure url="https://rss.art19.com/episodes/8e79a7b4-7656-45dc-8a1e-395df83c42e6.mp3?rss_browser=BAhJIgtQb2RpbW8GOgZFVA%3D%3D--dac5a739e2488b244c713a3c754b2eb4e45f1ea7" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/>
   <itunes:duration>00:28:54</itunes:duration>
   <itunes:image href="https://cdn.podimo.com/images/cc27b26d-88e9-4a74-bc86-4b2f026913a9_400x400.png"/>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Introducing: Hysterical</title>
   <description>Hysterical investigates a mysterious illness that spreads among a group of high school girls in upstate New York. What is causing their sudden, often violent symptoms? Is there something in the water or inside the school? Or is it “all in their head?” The series examines the outbreak in LeRoy, NY, believed by some to be the most severe case of mass hysteria since the Salem Witch Trials. In his search for answers, Dan Taberski (9/12, Missing Richard Simmons, Running from Cops) explores other seemingly inexplicable events of the last few years – CIA officers being crippled with nausea and vertigo; cops OD'ing from exposure to fentanyl – and discovers they’re far more connected than we realize.




From Wondery and Pineapple Street Studios, this 7-part series forces us to grapple with the mysteries of our own minds, and reckon with a contagion that we thought was long dead, but may be the defining disorder of our time.




Follow Hysterical on the Wondery App or wherever you get your podcasts. You can binge all episodes of Hysterical early and ad-free right now by joining Wondery+ in the Wondery App or on Apple Podcasts.

See Privacy Policy at https://art19.com/privacy [https://art19.com/privacy] and California Privacy Notice at https://art19.com/privacy#do-not-sell-my-info [https://art19.com/privacy#do-not-sell-my-info].</description>
   <guid isPermaLink="false">5034af56-02bf-4219-b419-de09af1274f0</guid>
   <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
   <enclosure url="https://rss.art19.com/episodes/7e8d4aef-17fc-4181-8ed6-36df421d90ef.mp3?rss_browser=BAhJIgtQb2RpbW8GOgZFVA%3D%3D--dac5a739e2488b244c713a3c754b2eb4e45f1ea7" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/>
   <itunes:duration>00:02:42</itunes:duration>
   <itunes:image href="https://cdn.podimo.com/images/de738d88-a6aa-41a0-bdc5-c2333f168e03_400x400.png"/>
  </item>
 </channel>
</rss>
