<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>Transforming Trauma</title>
  <description>In-depth conversations about how to help individuals and communities thrive after Complex Trauma. In a modern world beset by trauma and a legacy of suffering, conflict and disconnection, healing trauma can serve as a vehicle for personal and social transformation. Interviews with mental health and other helping professionals who are using the NeuroAffective Relational Model® (NARM®), as well as other prominent trauma specialists, will highlight the current efforts to address the legacy of childhood, relational, cultural and intergenerational trauma. These leaders in the Trauma-Informed Care movement will guide listeners through the diverse ways they are supporting individuals, couples, families and communities in order to actualize Post-Traumatic Growth. Whether you are a healthcare professional, an educator, a parent, a public policy maker, a trauma survivor, or someone interested in personal healing and social justice; this podcast will provide you with a map for increased resiliency, greater health outcomes, healthier relationships, personal growth and social change through transforming trauma. Hosted by the Complex Trauma Training Center.</description>
  <link>https://podimo.com/dk/shows/1ac627b2-f7cc-4eb4-a415-9b2873bab0d5</link>
  <image>
   <url>https://cdn.podimo.com/images/90af15a5-fad4-4b55-beea-2d228860a573_400x400.png</url>
   <title>Transforming Trauma</title>
   <link>https://podimo.com/dk/shows/1ac627b2-f7cc-4eb4-a415-9b2873bab0d5</link>
  </image>
  <item>
   <title>Honoring Resistance: The Wisdom of Defenses in Somatic &amp; Hakomi-Informed Trauma Healing with Shai Lavie, LMFT</title>
   <description>Trauma isn't just an event—it’s a complex, living pattern woven through our bodies, minds, and relationships. What if the path to healing isn’t about breaking down defenses or pushing past resistance, but about honoring those very protections as parts of our whole self?

 

Shai Lavie’s journey illuminates this radical shift. As a Hakomi and Somatic Experiencing therapist, Shai learned that trauma work flourishes when we stop battling our clients’ “barriers” and instead bring curiosity and compassion to every part of their experience—even the parts that resist change. Imagine your nervous system not as a malfunctioning engine to be fixed, but as a profound intelligence signaling what it needs to survive and adapt.

 

In practice, this means holding space for a client’s “resistance”, listening deeply to these “barriers” with genuine inquiry: “What wisdom might be present here? What story is this body telling me?” Such an approach transforms therapy from a power struggle into a collaborative voyage, where client and therapist become co-captains rowing in harmony, not opposition.

 

This relational, respectful method aligns beautifully with the NeuroAffective Relational Model® (NARM®) principles—where healing happens in connection, at the client’s pace, and through mindful presence. It invites us all, as therapists and healers, to recalibrate our role: to cultivate safety not by conquering defenses, but by embracing them, fostering agency within the authentic self.

 

If you’re a mental health professional eager to deepen your understanding of complex trauma and transform your therapeutic practice, we invite you to explore the upcoming NARM Therapist Trainings at the Complex Trauma Training Center. Join a community committed to growing both professionally and personally—where we learn that healing is not about fighting against our adaptive Self, but reconnecting with the resilient, compassionate, authentic Self.</description>
   <guid isPermaLink="false">a4f0c217-0798-5f7f-b3e8-79b9ce13aef3</guid>
   <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
   <enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/transformingtrauma/1759885173602_TTP_172_ShaiLavie.mp3?dest-id=1801064" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/>
   <itunes:duration>00:53:13</itunes:duration>
   <itunes:image href="https://cdn.podimo.com/images/e3bfcad6-83cd-402d-b382-17f144ce238d_400x400.png"/>
  </item>
 </channel>
</rss>
