<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>Transforming Trauma</title>
  <description>In-depth conversations about how to help individuals and communities thrive after Complex Trauma. In a modern world beset by trauma and a legacy of suffering, conflict and disconnection, healing trauma can serve as a vehicle for personal and social transformation. Interviews with mental health and other helping professionals who are using the NeuroAffective Relational Model® (NARM®), as well as other prominent trauma specialists, will highlight the current efforts to address the legacy of childhood, relational, cultural and intergenerational trauma. These leaders in the Trauma-Informed Care movement will guide listeners through the diverse ways they are supporting individuals, couples, families and communities in order to actualize Post-Traumatic Growth. Whether you are a healthcare professional, an educator, a parent, a public policy maker, a trauma survivor, or someone interested in personal healing and social justice; this podcast will provide you with a map for increased resiliency, greater health outcomes, healthier relationships, personal growth and social change through transforming trauma. Hosted by the Complex Trauma Training Center.</description>
  <link>https://podimo.com/dk/shows/1ac627b2-f7cc-4eb4-a415-9b2873bab0d5</link>
  <image>
   <url>https://cdn.podimo.com/images/90af15a5-fad4-4b55-beea-2d228860a573_400x400.png</url>
   <title>Transforming Trauma</title>
   <link>https://podimo.com/dk/shows/1ac627b2-f7cc-4eb4-a415-9b2873bab0d5</link>
  </image>
  <item>
   <title>Honoring Resistance: The Wisdom of Defenses in Somatic &amp; Hakomi-Informed Trauma Healing with Shai Lavie, LMFT</title>
   <description>Trauma isn't just an event—it’s a complex, living pattern woven through our bodies, minds, and relationships. What if the path to healing isn’t about breaking down defenses or pushing past resistance, but about honoring those very protections as parts of our whole self?

 

Shai Lavie’s journey illuminates this radical shift. As a Hakomi and Somatic Experiencing therapist, Shai learned that trauma work flourishes when we stop battling our clients’ “barriers” and instead bring curiosity and compassion to every part of their experience—even the parts that resist change. Imagine your nervous system not as a malfunctioning engine to be fixed, but as a profound intelligence signaling what it needs to survive and adapt.

 

In practice, this means holding space for a client’s “resistance”, listening deeply to these “barriers” with genuine inquiry: “What wisdom might be present here? What story is this body telling me?” Such an approach transforms therapy from a power struggle into a collaborative voyage, where client and therapist become co-captains rowing in harmony, not opposition.

 

This relational, respectful method aligns beautifully with the NeuroAffective Relational Model® (NARM®) principles—where healing happens in connection, at the client’s pace, and through mindful presence. It invites us all, as therapists and healers, to recalibrate our role: to cultivate safety not by conquering defenses, but by embracing them, fostering agency within the authentic self.

 

If you’re a mental health professional eager to deepen your understanding of complex trauma and transform your therapeutic practice, we invite you to explore the upcoming NARM Therapist Trainings at the Complex Trauma Training Center. Join a community committed to growing both professionally and personally—where we learn that healing is not about fighting against our adaptive Self, but reconnecting with the resilient, compassionate, authentic Self.</description>
   <guid isPermaLink="false">a4f0c217-0798-5f7f-b3e8-79b9ce13aef3</guid>
   <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
   <enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/transformingtrauma/1759885173602_TTP_172_ShaiLavie.mp3?dest-id=1801064" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/>
   <itunes:duration>00:53:13</itunes:duration>
   <itunes:image href="https://cdn.podimo.com/images/e3bfcad6-83cd-402d-b382-17f144ce238d_400x400.png"/>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Beyond Disorder: Redefining Identity, Meaning, and Healing with Dr. David Puder</title>
   <description>“The work we do is meaningful, sometimes difficult, but it's the best work to do.” - Dr. David Puder

On this episode of Transforming Trauma, Emily Ruth welcomes psychiatrist and psychotherapist Dr. David Puder to explore the clinical realities of complex trauma and the slow, often gritty path toward healing. Drawing on decades of hospital and outpatient experience, Dr. Puder offers candor and practical wisdom for clinicians and caring professionals who feel the weight of this work.

The pair discuss how complex developmental trauma shows up as dissociation and psychogenic symptoms rather than classic shock-based PTSD, how medical identities can eclipse a person’s strengths, and ways to help families shift out of illness-based roles. You’ll hear how dreams and creative writing can reveal disavowed material, why rare countertransference reactions are clinical clues, and how therapist reflective function — the ability to make meaning of inner reactions — predicts treatment impact. Dr. Puder also explains practical tools he developed, including a Connection Index for clinical teams, and offers concrete examples of converting medical patients into psychotherapy patients so they can reclaim agency and a life beyond diagnosis.

We invite you to listen to the full episode and follow Transforming Trauma on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, YouTube, or your favorite podcast app.

***

SPACE:

SPACE is an Inner Development Program of Support and Self-Discovery for Therapists on the Personal, Interpersonal, and Transpersonal Levels offered by the Complex Trauma Training Center. This experiential learning program offers an immersive group experience designed to cultivate space for self-care, community support, and deepening vitality in our professional role as therapists. Learn more about how to join.

***

The Complex Trauma Training Center: https://complextraumatrainingcenter.com

View upcoming trainings: https://complextraumatrainingcenter.com/schedule/

***

The Complex Trauma Training Center (CTTC) is a professional organization providing clinical training, education, consultation, and mentorship for psychotherapists and mental health professionals working with individuals and communities impacted by Adverse Childhood Experiences (ACEs) and Complex Trauma (C-PTSD). CTTC provides NARM® Therapist and NARM® Master Therapist Training programs, as well as ongoing monthly groups in support of those learning NARM. CTTC offers a depth-oriented professional community for those seeking a supportive network of therapists focused on three levels of shared human experience: personal, interpersonal &amp; transpersonal. The Transforming Trauma podcast embodies the spirit of CTTC – best described by its three keywords: depth, connection, and heart - and offers guidance to those interested in effective, transformational trauma-informed care.

We want to connect with you!

Facebook  https://www.facebook.com/complextraumatrainingcenter/

Instagram  https://www.instagram.com/complextraumatrainingcenter/

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/company/complex-trauma-training-center/

YouTube https://www.youtube.com/@ComplexTraumaTrainingCenter

X https://x.com/CTTC_Training</description>
   <guid isPermaLink="false">c85436da-b58a-5b20-a14d-c850ad2411ad</guid>
   <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
   <enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/transformingtrauma/TTP25091003AM_David_Puder_Horizontal_1.mp3?dest-id=1801064" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/>
   <itunes:duration>01:37:25</itunes:duration>
   <itunes:image href="https://cdn.podimo.com/images/b929cec3-7369-4f41-a888-843a92ab781a_400x400.png"/>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Celebrating Agency, Therapist Self-Care, and the new NARM Workbook with Brad Kammer, CTTC Training Director</title>
   <description>&quot;Our greatest hope is that NARM® can lead to increasing opportunities for connection, healing, and transformation.&quot; - Brad Kammer



On this episode of Transforming Trauma, Stephanie Klein is joined by Brad Kammer, Training Director at the Complex Trauma Training Center, to discuss the newly released workbook for healing developmental trauma—an accessible resource distilling the core principles and clinical tools of the NeuroAffective Relational Model®. Brad shares the intention behind this third book in the NARM canon: creating a user-friendly, desk-side reference for clinicians and individuals seeking to understand and apply the NARM approach to complex and developmental trauma.



The conversation traces the evolution from the original &quot;Healing Developmental Trauma&quot; text—introducing the theoretical basis of NARM—through to the more clinical &quot;Practical Guide for Healing Developmental Trauma,&quot; and now to this practical workbook designed for everyday integration. Brad explains how the new workbook balances clinical exercises for practitioners with reflective prompts for personal growth, making it suitable for therapists, clients, and any individual interested in self-healing. Together, Stephanie and Brad reflect on how these resources support both professional development and inner exploration, highlighting the ripple effects of personal transformation in broader contexts.



We invite you to listen to the full episode and follow Transforming Trauma on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, YouTube, or your favorite podcast app.

***

SPACE:

SPACE is an Inner Development Program of Support and Self-Discovery for Therapists on the Personal, Interpersonal, and Transpersonal Levels offered by the Complex Trauma Training Center. This experiential learning program offers an immersive group experience designed to cultivate space for self-care, community support, and deepening vitality in our professional role as therapists. Learn more about how to join.

***

The Complex Trauma Training Center:

https://complextraumatrainingcenter.com

View upcoming trainings:

https://complextraumatrainingcenter.com/schedule/

***

The Complex Trauma Training Center (CTTC) is a professional organization providing clinical training, education, consultation, and mentorship for psychotherapists and mental health professionals working with individuals and communities impacted by Adverse Childhood Experiences (ACEs) and Complex Trauma (C-PTSD). CTTC provides NARM® Therapist and NARM® Master Therapist Training programs, as well as ongoing monthly groups in support of those learning NARM. CTTC offers a depth-oriented professional community for those seeking a supportive network of therapists focused on three levels of shared human experience: personal, interpersonal &amp; transpersonal. The Transforming Trauma podcast embodies the spirit of CTTC – best described by its three keywords: depth, connection, and heart - and offers guidance to those interested in effective, transformational trauma-informed care.

We want to connect with you!

Facebook

https://www.facebook.com/complextraumatrainingcenter/

Instagram

https://www.instagram.com/complextraumatrainingcenter/

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/company/complex-trauma-training-center/

YouTube

https://www.youtube.com/@ComplexTraumaTrainingCenter

X

https://x.com/CTTC_Training</description>
   <guid isPermaLink="false">9672e05c-5c1c-5051-821d-7ec7ebfd36c3</guid>
   <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
   <enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/transformingtrauma/TTP25092211AM_Brad_Kammer_-_Stefanie_Klein.mp3?dest-id=1801064" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/>
   <itunes:duration>00:34:25</itunes:duration>
   <itunes:image href="https://cdn.podimo.com/images/88d5bf46-f202-47eb-91c0-c833cfe25b7d_400x400.png"/>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>Harnessing Implicit Memory for Trauma Healing with Dr. Abi Blakeslee</title>
   <description>&quot;Trauma can be a gateway for transformation, and it's one of the things that I am passionate about.&quot; – Abi Blakeslee On this episode of Transforming Trauma, host Emily Ruth sits down with Dr. Abi Blakeslee, a leader in the field of trauma recovery and somatic psychology recognized for her clinical research and teaching. Dr. Blakeslee shares her deep exploration of implicit memory—the non-conscious processes shaping movement, emotion, and survival patterns—and explains how harnessing implicit memory offers new and practical pathways to healing trauma. Drawing from Somatic Experiencing, neuroscience, and her own research, Dr. Blakeslee breaks down the branches of implicit memory—procedural, priming, associative, and more—and clarifies their relevance in trauma and recovery. The conversation explores how clinicians can support present-moment, embodied &quot;new learning&quot; that rewires automatic responses and fosters positive transformation. Listeners will hear practical strategies to increase clients' interoceptive awareness, cultivate self-compassion, and repair ruptures through embodied, relational experiences. Dr. Blakeslee emphasizes the importance of helping clients reconnect with their essential self, shifting the focus from merely resolving the past to building new implicit memories of agency, connection, and vitality. Together they discuss the flexibility of integrating these neurobiological insights into diverse modalities—including Somatic Experiencing, Attachment Theory, Psychodynamic Therapy, and beyond—to deepen agency and nurture post-traumatic growth, especially in cases of developmental and complex trauma. Throughout, Dr. Blakeslee underscores the healing power of gentle attention, relational attunement, and compassion—offering a hopeful framework for practitioners and clients alike. We invite you to listen to the full episode and follow Transforming Trauma on Apple Podcasts, Spotify, YouTube, or your favorite podcast app. *** **SPACE:** SPACE is an Inner Development Program of Support and Self-Discovery for Therapists on the Personal, Interpersonal, and Transpersonal Levels offered by the Complex Trauma Training Center. This experiential learning program offers an immersive group experience designed to cultivate space for self-care, community support, and deepening vitality in our professional role as therapists. Learn more about how to join. *** **The Complex Trauma Training Center:** https://complextraumatrainingcenter.com [https://complextraumatrainingcenter.com/] **View upcoming trainings:** https://complextraumatrainingcenter.com/schedule/ [https://complextraumatrainingcenter.com/schedule/] *** The Complex Trauma Training Center (CTTC) is a professional organization providing clinical training, education, consultation, and mentorship for psychotherapists and mental health professionals working with individuals and communities impacted by Adverse Childhood Experiences (ACEs) and Complex Trauma (C-PTSD). CTTC provides NARM® Therapist and NARM® Master Therapist Training programs, as well as ongoing monthly groups in support of those learning NARM. CTTC offers a depth-oriented professional community for those seeking a supportive network of therapists focused on three levels of shared human experience: personal, interpersonal &amp; transpersonal. The Transforming Trauma podcast embodies the spirit of CTTC – best described by its three keywords: depth, connection, and heart - and offers guidance to those interested in effective, transformational trauma-informed care. *** We want to connect with you! **Facebook ** https://www.facebook.com/complextraumatrainingcenter/ [https://www.facebook.com/complextraumatrainingcenter/] **Instagram ** https://www.instagram.com/complextraumatrainingcenter/ [https://www.instagram.com/complextraumatrainingcenter/] **LinkedIn** https://www.linkedin.com/company/complex-trauma-training-center/ [https://www.linkedin.com/company/complex-trauma-training-center/] **YouTube** https://www.youtube.com/@ComplexTraumaTrainingCenter [https://www.youtube.com/@ComplexTraumaTrainingCenter] **X** https://x.com/CTTC_Training [https://x.com/CTTC_Training]</description>
   <guid isPermaLink="false">4ce0ed94-edde-5df0-bb0e-617c2f47755e</guid>
   <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
   <enclosure url="https://traffic.libsyn.com/secure/transformingtrauma/TTP25091003AM_Abi_Blakeslee_-audio_156.mp3?dest-id=1801064" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/>
   <itunes:duration>01:01:17</itunes:duration>
   <itunes:image href="https://cdn.podimo.com/images/bb380f5a-6146-410f-8b19-5313a322d537_400x400.png"/>
  </item>
 </channel>
</rss>
