<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>Transfer Talk</title>
  <description>Transfer Talk is a podcast from Sky Sports News which features debate and analysis from some of the most well connected reporters in the football world throughout the transfer windows.We dig into the biggest storylines, both in the Premier League and around Europe, as we keep you up to date on all the latest developments.Transfer Talk is a Sky Sports podcast. Listen to every episode here: skysports.com/transfer-talkYou can listen to Transfer Talk on your smart speaker by saying &quot;ask Global Player to play Transfer Talk&quot;.For all the latest football news, head to skysports.com/footballFor advertising opportunities email: skysportspodcasts@sky.uk</description>
  <link>https://podimo.com/dk/shows/29577f67-99ee-4279-9f7a-83e618c63e61</link>
  <image>
   <url>https://cdn.podimo.com/images/53a32f5f-10c8-4494-abe1-348a11a71144_400x400.png</url>
   <title>Transfer Talk</title>
   <link>https://podimo.com/dk/shows/29577f67-99ee-4279-9f7a-83e618c63e61</link>
  </image>
  <item>
   <title>January window previewed: Antoine Semenyo to Liverpool, Man Utd or Man City? | Mo Salah to leave Liverpool? | Kobbie Mainoo future &amp; more!</title>
   <description>Dharmesh Sheth is joined by legendary journalist Henry Winter and ESPN's Sam Tighe to preview the January transfer window. The future of Bournemouth's Antoine Semenyo will be one of the biggest stories of the window as Manchester United, Manchester City and Liverpool all look to trigger his £65 million release clause. Mo Salah still faces an uncertain future at Anfield despite the uneasy truce with Arne Slot, the Reds might well look to reignite interested in Crystal Palace's Marc Guehi and will Kobbie Mainoo look for a way out of Old Trafford due to lack of game time? Plus, Aston Villa's Unai Emery wants the club to be active in the window despite potential PSR constraints, West Ham look to add a striker to help ease relegation worries and Oliver Glasner at Selhurst Park wants to add some bodies ahead of a fixture pile-up.

Transfer Talk is a Sky Sports podcast. Listen to every episode here: skysports.com/transfer-talk [https://www.skysports.com/podcasts/36578/11933958/transfer-talk]

You can listen to Transfer Talk on your smart speaker by saying &quot;ask Global Player to play Transfer Talk&quot;.

For all the latest football news, head to skysports.com/football [http://www.skysports.com/football]

For advertising opportunities email: skysportspodcasts@sky.uk</description>
   <guid isPermaLink="false">429b1f03-95c1-5064-8203-dc666c7e51c9</guid>
   <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 21:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
   <enclosure url="https://api.spreaker.com/download/episode/69172970/final_transfer_talk_22_dec.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mpeg"/>
   <itunes:duration>00:52:54</itunes:duration>
   <itunes:image href="https://cdn.podimo.com/images/53a32f5f-10c8-4494-abe1-348a11a71144_400x400.png"/>
  </item>
 </channel>
</rss>
